=The Road to Splendor=
(Adapted from China Literature author
Zhizhi's novel of the same name)
=Episode 36=
This is a restricted area.
No unauthorized entry.
(Imperial Decree)
All unrelated personnel,
leave immediately.
Search!
(Grand Secretary Yu is finished.)
Mr. Zhao is back.
Don't worry, Mr. Zhao.
The entire household
is intact.
I'm back.
It's good to have you back.
(Yu Residence)
Did you bring it?
Give it to me.
No father harms his own child.
Is this really the only way?
Do you think I want this?
Look at what has become
of the world outside!
His Majesty is just waiting for a reason
to confiscate our estate
and fill the treasury.
Now is the time
to sacrifice a part to save the whole.
Give it to me.
Master,
you must keep him alive.
Please, you must keep him alive.
Madam.
Father.
I never knew you liked Guangling Melody.
I happen to have
a fragment of Ji Kang's original score.
Tomorrow,
I will get it for you.
But didn't you always disapprove
of my indulgence in music?
Why today...?
A father and son share a bond.
What you desire,
I'll give it to you.
Likewise,
what I desire,
Jingxiu,
you must do your utmost to fulfill.
(Confession)
(Your Majesty, I, Yu Jingxiu,
stand guilty and await your judgment.)
Father, you can't be serious.
Every charge on this confession
is a grave one.
This means death.
And besides,
if I confess and sign,
no one will believe it.
Jingxiu,
this is only a formality.
His Majesty made his intentions clear
in court today.
He wants to fill the treasury
by confiscating our assets.
He allowed me to come home tonight
precisely for this.
Who confesses no longer matters.
As for no one believing you...
You served
as a secretary
in the Ministry of Revenue.
Your duty was auditing revenue
and expenditures,
particularly the salt tax.
It falls within your authority.
It is only natural.
In the end,
you still want to discard me?
Jingxiu,
I have nowhere left to turn.
I have no other choice.
If you confess,
I will do everything in my power
to save your life.
And I will leave you a foundation
to rise again.
But if I
go to prison and face punishment,
the Yu family will be finished.
Jingxiu,
you must think of the bigger picture.
No!
Jingxiu!
Where are you running?
Can you really escape?
Father.
There must be someone more suitable.
What about Yu Huaian?
Ms. Shu?
Chengxin?
He's been with me for years.
I can convince him.
You're too naive.
Yu Huaian, Ms. Shu and Chengxin.
They are all beneath us.
Now we must offer up
someone from the top
to appease the people
and uphold the Emperor's authority.
Do you understand?
I will find someone.
I will find the right person.
There's no time.
Sign it.
Father!
Don't lie to me.
You claim to love me,
but you've always treated me
as a piece of meat
to be devoured.
What nonsense are you saying?
You...
Didn't you want to go to Ganlin Town?
Sign the confession,
and I will send you there
to keep you safe.
No.
I won't sign!
Yu Guodong,
if you do this,
aren't you afraid
of breaking Mother's heart?
Father.
Father, what's wrong?
Father?
Father.
Father, I didn't mean it.
I didn't mean it.
(Qingli Hall of Learning)
Father.
You were forced by circumstances.
Madam, you had no other choice.
In ancient times, sons sacrificed
for their parents.
They risked their lives to save them.
Young Master is well-read.
He knows what matters most.
Young Master.
Mother.
Master.
Master!
What... what happened?
What happened?
What exactly happened?
What happened? Tell me.
Speak!
Mother,
it wasn't me.
Father fell on his own.
I didn't mean it.
Mother.
How could this happen?
Master.
Master!
How could this happen?
Mother.
What's done is done.
Killing one's father is a grave crime.
Please save me, Mother.
Why couldn't it have been you?
So you had it all planned
from the start.
The big fish eating the small one.
But you didn't expect
the small fish to survive.
None of you wanted me.
No...
Fan is gone.
Wu is gone too.
Father wanted to discard me,
and you went along with it.
But Mother,
I have disappointed you again.
This time,
no matter what,
you have to help me.
My Lord.
We arrived too late.
(Great Virtue Brings Fortune)
(Your Majesty, I, Yu Guodong,
confess my crimes.)
(My crimes are too numerous to count.
I deserve death.)
(Yu Guodong's final words.)
Suicide out of guilt?
He would actually do it?
Where are Madam Yu and Yu Jingxiu?
Search.
(Great Virtue Brings Fortune)
Last night,
my late husband and my son
had an argument.
I did overhear
something about "turn oneself in."
I thought it was just normal affairs.
I never expected that this morning,
he would take his own life.
(Boundless Longevity)
Yu Guodong
has been corrupt for years.
Did you and your son
truly know nothing?
He always made his own decisions.
Even I, his wife,
could barely see into his affairs.
But yesterday,
my son happened to discover something.
I...
I saw it with my own eyes last night.
My father was meeting privately
with his protege.
I had...
I had intended
to persuade him to turn back.
But I never expected...
As a court official,
I could not bear
to watch a top minister
remain stubborn and harm the court.
The law has no room for personal ties.
This matter
must be handled impartially
to restore proper order.
But
he is still my father.
Loyalty and filial piety
cannot both be fulfilled.
If Your Majesty does not believe me,
then let me
(Boundless Longevity)
bear my father's punishment!
I was foolish.
I failed to notice sooner.
My son exposed his own father
and wanted to save him from ruin.
But a son's heart is not made of stone.
How could he not feel the pain?
If the court must punish someone,
Grand Empress Dowager,
please, as a mother myself,
let me
bear the punishment for my son!
Mother.
Please, Your Majesty.
Let me be punished!
No, Mother. You must not.
Mother.
Enough.
I understand everything now.
The Emperor has always been
fair in rewarding and punishing.
He will give the Yu family
a just outcome.
I
will abide by your decree.
You may go.
Mother.
Your Majesty,
what do you think?
(Boundless Longevity)
They were all raised
on the people's blood and sweat.
There's no such thing
as sacrificing kin for justice.
It's just a desperate act,
cutting off a limb to survive.
Madam Yu
is a sharp woman.
If we spare her and her son,
her money
will be given up more willingly.
If we leave her no way out,
she may just put it all
into the coffin.
Yu Guodong
is dead and can no longer speak.
Confiscate his assets
to serve as a warning.
In the future,
officials should take this as a lesson,
and let it always
serve as a reminder.
(Yu Residence)
(By the grace of Heaven,)
(the Emperor decrees:)
(Yu Guodong,)
(Yu Residence)
(guilty of heinous crimes,)
(now)
(stands convicted of multiple offenses.)
(His assets are confiscated)
(and forfeited to the treasury.)
(His son, Yu Jingxiu,)
(and wife, Shu,)
(for their role in exposing the crimes,)
(are granted a pardon)
(but reduced to commoners.)
(All other servants)
(May Virtue and Grace Endure)
(are to be banished
fifteen hundred kilometers.)
(Thus decreed.)
(Yu Residence)
Move out.
Now it's your turn to laugh at me.
What's in that box?
The recipe for Chastity Tonic?
It's my mother's keepsake.
I want her
to bear witness.
About the Fifth Madam's matter,
I owe you an apology.
But for other things,
we traded blow for blow.
I see no fault in my actions.
Since ancient times, the victor rules.
Now that I have lost,
I am at your mercy.
Have you come to take my life?
I like to think
I know you well.
You are not afraid of death.
What you fear
is losing that last shred of pride.
Living with nothing left
would be worse
than death itself.
Between you and me,
we're each other's teachers,
rivals,
and friends.
We never became
mother-in-law and daughter-in-law,
but we turned out to be kindred spirits.
That is quite interesting.
There is a touch of loneliness
in your words.
In this world,
who is not lonely?
Have you ever thought
about what kind of person
you want to become?
When I was young,
I once took you as my role model.
I thought a woman
should be like you,
running the household,
knowing when to advance
and when to retreat,
and even taking charge
among men.
And then?
Then I understood.
Even you, Madam,
are nothing more
than a proxy for men's power,
an ornament
to their glory.
Today, I have come to thank you.
Thank you for shattering
my illusions back then.
You kept me
from repeating your mistakes.
Your words...
If I had a child like you,
perhaps I would better understand them.
If I were your daughter,
you would still be dissatisfied with me.
Your way of thinking
and acting would be just the same.
Madam.
Madam!
I can no longer care for you!
I cannot bear to leave you, Madam!
Take care, Madam!
This is
for Ji.
Your family assets have been seized.
Now you must care for your mother
and raise your child.
My wife sends this on behalf of Fan.
Are you here to humiliate me?
If you see kindness
as humiliation,
then yes.
I am humiliating you.
But in this world,
who has never been humiliated?
Just think of it as walking
a path others have walked.
If you cannot even bear this,
you might as well
return Ji to his mother.
(Yu Residence)
Yu Guodong has been brought down.
I am greatly pleased.
I hereby confer upon Zhao Ling
the honorary Third‑Rank General Zhaoyi
and bestow an imperial patent,
along with a new residence.
Your Majesty,
please consider this carefully.
I beg your forgiveness,
but I cannot accept.
You refuse my rewards,
and now you wish to resign?
Do you think I have no one else
to serve me in this court?
Your Majesty, please calm yourself.
I was once nothing but an outlaw.
By Your Majesty's boundless grace,
I was elevated to the court.
But the court is a place
where one treads on thin ice.
I have struggled to navigate
and often felt inadequate.
At times, I was drawn into conflicts
that harmed the very people
I wished to protect.
I never had grand ambitions.
All I have ever wanted
is
to be with the one I love,
watching the days pass
and growing old in peace.
There are many worthy ministers
who can serve as wise counselors.
They will understand
the affairs of state
and help build a prosperous era.
I
humbly
ask for Your Majesty's grace.
Please grant me permission
to retire from service
and fulfill this one wish.
You may step out.
All right.
Your heart is not in this.
No matter how I try to keep you,
it would be in vain.
I thank Your Majesty for your grace.
You may go.
Madam Wei, how did you win again?
How do you win every round?
Exactly.
Go and prepare.
Yes.
I feel like switching seats with you.
It's not about the seat.
Madam,
Master has returned.
He even changed into fresh clothes.
Let's stop here.
It's getting late.
Then
shall we meet another day?
Sure.
Another day.
This lady here,
are you
waiting for your husband?
I wonder,
how was your luck today?
Luck in gambling
means less luck in love.
I kept winning today.
What do you think?
Come on.
Sit here.
Good.
Come on.
Let me
rub it for you.
Were you the one
who helped me with the recent matter?
Who doesn't know
about the things you've been doing?
But
I already had Father
pull your name list
out of the pile.
Really?
Move.
Madam,
you are too good to me.
Then you know what to do from now on?
I'll be good and listen to you.
(Xianji Salt Shop)
Fine salt,
twenty copper coins per catty.
Come again.
Sure.
Sir,
has the salt reform
really been settled?
The court gazette
came down yesterday.
From now on, the salt
will no longer be controlled
by one family alone.
Alright.
Fine salt, twenty copper coins
per catty.
Just a while ago,
fine salt was seventy
or eighty copper coins per catty.
(Xianji Salt Shop)
Now,
you can buy it for twenty.
With the Yu family's fall,
and the salt administration cleansed,
our lives
are getting better.
Indeed.
(Double Happiness)
Thank you for your hospitality,
Commander Wang.
(Double Happiness)
Thank you, Commander Wang.
Come on.
I'm glad you could come.
Go on home now.
Alright.
Let's go.
Easy.
My dear,
do you remember the persimmon tree
planted in the backyard
after we married?
Of course I do.
You once said to learn
from the persimmon.
The more it endures the frost,
the sweeter it becomes.
Wrong,
I was wrong.
(Double Happiness)
Look at the persimmon.
When fully ripe, it falls to the ground.
It never clings to the branch.
So
the persimmon's worth
is not in its sweetness,
but in its falling.
To fall and to rise again
is nature's way.
This is to you
and a broad state of mind.
To you, Madam.
(Double Happiness)
When the Yu family fell,
everyone scattered.
I haven't heard
what happened to that Young Madam Yu.
Could she have
quietly died in some well?
I heard,
before the Yu family fell,
she was sent off to the estate.
Even if she hasn't been punished,
she's probably
out there working the fields.
Wasn't she the one who compiled
the Dongshan Poetry Talks,
the talented Fan Yake?
That's her.
That book you mentioned
people only bought it to prop up a table
when the Yu family was powerful.
That's not right.
Fan Yake may have married
into the Yu family,
but she came from Huaying.
She is the daughter of the great scholar
Fan Kun.
She excels in painting,
capturing flowers and plants
with such life,
and her poetry is exquisite.
What does her talent
have to do with the Yu family?
This person
looks familiar.
Could she be
Fan?
My Lady,
the new shipment of brocade has arrived.
They're waiting for you
to check and shelve it.
I never imagined
I would ever live
a life like this.
With leisure,
and with money.
Let's go.
(Spirit Tablet of My Late Brother
Yang Yucheng)
(Spirit Tablet of the Late Mother Yang)
(Spirit Tablet of My Late Brother
Zhou Ruixiang)
- Mr. Jin.
Take a look at this.
Mr. Jin.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Take care.
Why is Mr. Jin limping?
(Xie's Shop  Cliff Salt)
In the seventh year of Hongzhi,
a corrupt official was brought down.
Have you heard of it?
Mr. Jin beat the Dengwen Drum.
He sacrificed a leg,
but he did right by his brothers.
His salt is quite good.
Congratulations, Madam Mo.
Madam Mo.
Madam Mo, congratulations.
Congratulations.
Congrats on your son's success.
I'm so happy.
Congratulations.
Congrats.
Thank you, everyone.
I always knew
the Mo family
would produce a scholar.
Congratulations.
Congratulations to Young Master Mo.
Why are you crying over good news?
I'm happy.
Alright.
It's great news.
(Zhengxue Academy)
Master!
I passed!
Master.
I passed too!
We all passed!
Good.
Remember what I have taught you.
As officials,
you must be incorruptible and just,
and love the people as your own.
Do not be blinded by wealth
and lose sight of your true purpose.
Heaven
has opened countless paths for us.
Choose wisely.
Thank you, Master, for your guidance.
Master.
You see?
I am not
without talent for learning.
I just didn't like the imperial exams.
I think
teaching is good.
Yes.
Our master
is the best.
Senior brother,
congratulations on passing.
We should thank Master Fu.
(Letter-Writing Service)
Need a letter written?
Sir,
need a letter written?
I heard
you were a top scholar.
So
do you still charge
just three copper coins per letter?
He's the son of a convicted official.
It's generous enough
that he gets any business.
Yes.
I write and copy
at the market rate,
three copper coins per letter,
no matter how long.
Ji,
look,
this is the character for top scholar.
Study hard,
and one day, like your father,
you will top all three exams
and bring honor to the family.
Listen to me.
No matter what happens,
no matter when,
you must never lose your spirit.
Do you remember?
Remember?
The old lady looks good.
Yes.
She teaches her grandson every day.
She wants him to be a top scholar.
But her family ran afoul of the law.
For generations to come, none of them
can sit for the exams.
Is that true?
Greetings, ladies.
Stop staring.
Let's go.
Jingxiu, you're back.
Mother.
Come here.
Jingxiu,
I have found a match for you.
Though the family is not prominent,
the Ninth Young Lady Fu
is one I favor.
Listen to your mother.
A virtuous woman
blesses three generations.
In marriage,
choose virtue.
I will do as you say.
And you must remember too.
When you grow up,
your father will find you a good match.
A virtuous woman
blesses three generations.
In marriage,
choose virtue.
Be like your father...
I will do as you say.
You will top all three exams
and bring honor to the family.
I will do as you say.
When he grows up,
he must also find a good match.
A virtuous woman
blesses three generations.
In marriage,
choose virtue.
The wise delight in water,
the virtuous delight in mountains.
The wise are active,
the virtuous are still.
The wise find joy,
the virtuous live long.
(I never expected)
(that she could now settle her mind)
(in this remote place as an instructor.)
(From Miss Fan)
(to Young Madam Yu)
(to now Ms. Fan, the instructor.)
(Perhaps)
(this is who she truly is.)
Mother,
where is this?
This is where
I used to teach.
And where your father
made his name.
Teach me to read and write, Mother.
One day, I'll make my mark too,
and be remembered.
You, what do you want to be
when you grow up?
I want to be like you, Father,
a general, a high official.
Come on.
Careful.
Becoming a regional commander is good.
But the three of us,
living freely,
is also good.
To transcend the world,
you must first enter it.
You, when you grow up,
if you can be like your mother,
with a mind of her own,
even if you're not in the history books,
you'll still be a remarkable woman.
♪Once a bird in a cage,
longing for the boundless sky♪
♪To break through a thousand barriers
and cast off a life of illusion♪
♪Though I rack my brain with care,
fate still sways me here and there♪
Hold on tight.
Hold steady.
Sit tight, You.
Okay.
Let's go.
Father, higher!
Higher!
Alright.
♪Inviting frost to my temples,
veiling the face of bygone days.♪
♪Bearing wings through stormy tides,
wash away stain of false accusation♪
♪May all common folk share one roof,
every lantern rest in peace♪
♪Let this humble name carry me
through a life adrift♪
♪With wit and strategy,
I enter this game without regret♪
♪Though each move is forced upon me♪
♪May it buy the world
one moment's peace from the storm♪
♪I crave no clarity♪
♪From outside my soul♪
(Directed by Deng Ke)
(The End)
♪The past brushes by
like a falling leaf♪
♪So light, yet my steps still pause
for you♪
♪Through every rise and fall,
our memories remain without regret♪
♪Carved into the rings of time♪
♪How I wish I could stay
a little longer, but I can't♪
♪I turn away, afraid goodbye will fill
my eyes with tears♪
♪Etched deep within my heart,
yet buried without a word♪
♪The warmth of your hand in mine♪
♪Still makes us want to believe♪
♪One promise for a lifetime,
echoing long after we part♪
♪For one fleeting moment, I found you
in the crowd♪
♪Without a word, you lit up
half my life♪
♪In silence, a love too deep for words♪
♪Kept close within my heart♪
♪From now on, no one else
is worth waiting for♪
♪I turn away, afraid no one
will ever come home to me again♪
♪If we can build our future together,
no storm can chill my heart♪
♪The warmth of your hand in mine♪
♪Still makes us want to believe♪
♪One promise for a lifetime,
echoing long after we part♪